## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### **ADENIYI BELLA**



Q Wiesbaden, Germany



<u>Portfolio</u>



0178 9703022



✓ adeniyibella@gmail.com



## **PROFILE**

I am a dedicated and adaptable professional with experience in Software Development, Construction, Logistics, Operations, and Cloud solutions. With a background in Civil Engineering and a positive track record in multiple companies, I have obtained skills in project management, problem-solving, leadership qualities, and process optimization, particularly in fast-paced environments.

Before my master's studies, I gained extensive experience working on construction sites as a civil engineer and project manager. During my master, I worked in a research team at TUM, focusing on Al-driven point cloud labeling, in Amazon with focus on logistics and VIU Eyewears with focus on Operations.

After my master, I worked as a software developer at Wolff and Mueller, where I contributed to multiple software development projects. I have also contributed to a lot of other personal projects not tied to any company. Currently, I am an IT Specialist at ISL-Kocher GmbH with more focus on cloud solutions, but I am open to transitioning to a different role.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### IT Specialist

**ISL-Kocher GMBH (Siegen Germany)** 

Nov 2023 - Current

- Project Management: Set quarterly goals for the team that matches company goals, tracked the progress of projects, and adjusted project plans when needed to help the team perform well and complete projects successfully.
- UI/UX: Rapid UI/UX prototyped using Kendo UI components to visualize product design before development, gathered feedback from the team, and refined the UI based on the feedback, thereby reducing the need to hire a UI/UX designer and also minimizing code rewrites.
- Secured the database from unauthorized access by developing an API that restricts database access, ensuring only authenticated and authorized users can interact with it.
- Cloud development: Worked with cloud-based solutions (PaaS) in Azure, such as Azure AD B2C for identity management, Azure SWA for deploying frontend applications, Azure SQL Server and Azure blob storage for storing data, Azure Web App services for deploying backend applications, and Azure Devops pipelines for automating the build and deployment processes.

#### **Software Developer**

Wolff and Mueller (Stuttgart, Germany)

Jan 2022 - Oct 2023

- Improved the UI/UX of the Desite BIM product used internally within the company by leveraging Desite API(similar to Revit API).
- · Optimized the cost of storing large data by compressing it on the client side before sending it through the API to Azure Blob Storage. This approach minimizes database storage and data transfer costs and shifts compression/decompression processing to the client side.
- Implemented an algorithm that tracks the usage of all applications by workers, resulting in improved issue prioritization as we had a better overview of what applications are very popular with our users.
- · Enhanced user experience by automating repetitive manual processes, reducing the number of clicks required to complete a task. This improved the workflow and productivity of workers, as fewer clicks are required to perform the same action.

# Operations Associate VIU Eyewear (Munich, Germany)

- Conducted quality checks on eyewear products to ensure high standards before shipment.
- Picked, packed, and labeled eyewear products, ensuring timely and accurate order fulfillment.
- Assisted in daily logistics and warehouse operations, including inventory management, order processing, and stock control.
- Supported the returns and exchange process, verifying product condition and processing replacements or refunds.

#### **Warehouse Associate**

Jan 2020 - Nov 2020,

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

#### Amazon (Munich, Germany)

- Sorted, scanned, and packed parcels with high speed and precision, ensuring proper labeling for shipment.
- Worked flexible night shifts, ensuring smooth operations during off-peak hours and maintaining efficiency in 24/7 logistics processes.
- Assisted in problem-solving issues related to lost or misplaced packages to ensure successful deliveries.

## **PROJECTS**

- **Geohilfe-Project:** Contributed in the role of a software engineer to build a tool for the Deutsche Red Cross that enhances the geolocation of patients in emergency cases. The GitHub link to the project is <a href="here">here</a>.
- **Talent Haven:** Built an MVP of a digital platform, that connects students with research topics and working student positions at Deutsche Telekom IT. The GitHub link to the project is <a href="here">here</a>.
- GoalStream AI: Currently building a fully automated football highlights social media page (X, Instagram, Thread, and so on) that downloads videos from YouTube, stores them on Azure blob storage, upload videos to my social media pages via Azure functions, and optimize engagement strategies to grow my social media pages
- 3D Viewer: Built a simple 3D model viewer by extending the three JS library. Implemented basic functionalities like measurement, filtering, and clipping planes. The viewer can be tested with an IFC file here.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science in Civil Engineering

Apr 2019 - Oct 2022

Technical University Munchen (Germany)

BIM (Building information modelling)

### **Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering**

Jan 2007 - Aug 2012

FUNAAB (Nigeria)

CAD Softwares Programming

## **SKILLS**

- Technical Skills: Microsoft Office Suite, Azure Cloud, Database Management, HTML/CSS, JavaScript
- Languages: English (Fluent), German (B1-B2)